<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font>Hurry!
快點
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> Do you not understand? Krypton's core is collapsing.
你們不明白嗎？氪利普頓星的核心要崩塌了
We may only have a matter of weeks.I warned you.
可能只剩幾星期，我警告過你們
Harvesting the core was suicide.It has accelerated
採集核心物質是自殺行為，那加速了內爆的進程
-  the process of implosion. - Our energy reserves
備用能源已消耗殆盡
were exhausted.What would you have us do, El?
你要我們怎麼辦，艾爾？
Look to the stars, like our ancestors did.
尋找其他星球，像我們祖先那樣
There are habitable worlds within reach. We can begin by using the old outposts.
咫尺內就有適合居住的星球，可從舊前哨站著手
Are you seriously suggesting that we evacuate the entire planet?
你該不會真建議我們疏散整個星球吧？
No. Everybody here is already dead.
不，這裡的人早就沒救了
Give me control of the Codex. I will ensure the survival of our race.
讓我管理生育法典 我會確保種族得以延續
There is still hope.
希望仍然存在
I have held that hope in my hands.
我曾以雙手握住希望
<font color="#D900D9">(GUARDS GRUNT)</font>
This council has been disbanded.
這個議會解散了
On whose authority?
誰下的令？
Mine.
是我
The rest of you will be tried and punished accordingly.
你們都會依序受審和接受懲罰
What are you doing, Zod? This is madness.
你在幹嘛，薩德？ 這太瘋狂了
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> - What I should have done  years ago.
我幾年前就該這麼做了
These lawmakers with their endless debates have lead Krypton to ruin.
這些光說不練的立法官員害克利普頓萬劫不復
And if your forces prevail you'll be the leader of nothing.
就算你政變成功人都殺光了，你要領導誰？
Then join me.
那就加入我
Help me save our race. We'll start anew.
幫助我拯救我族，我們可以重新開始
We'll sever the degenerative bloodlines that led us to this state.
砍斷害我們淪落至此的殘敗血脈
And who will decide which bloodlines survive, Zod?
那由誰決定哪些血脈該延續？
You?
你嗎？
Don't do this, El.
別這樣，艾爾
The last thing I want is for us to be enemies.
我不希望我們成為敵人
You have abandoned the principles that bound us together.
你摒棄了我們結合的原則
You've taken up the sword against your own people.
你竟揮劍指向自己人
I will honor the man you once were, Zod
我會尊敬過去的你，薩德
not this monster you've become.
而不是現在這個怪物
Take him away.
把他帶走
Sir? Is everything all right?
Out of the way.
滾開
I said
我說
先生，一切都好嗎？
Get me Lara.
幫我接通蘿拉
Jor. Behind you.
喬，小心後面
<font color="#D900D9">(YELLS)</font>
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> Lara, you have to ready the launch.
蘿拉，妳得準備發射太空船
I'll be with you as soon as I can.
我會儘快趕回去
H'Raka!
哈拉卡
<font color="#D900D9">(H'RAKA BELLOWS)</font>
- Can you see the Codex? <font color="#808080">KELEX:</font>  It's just beneath the central hub.
- 你看得到法典嗎？ - 就在中心樞紐下面，先生
But I'm compelled to warn you.
但我想警告您
Breaching the genesis chamber is a Class-B crime
私闖創始室是B級重罪
Nobody cares anymore, Kelex. The world is about to come to an end.
已經沒人在乎了，姬莉絲，這星球就要毀滅了
<font color="#D900D9">(HIGH-PITCHED HUMMING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SOLDIER:</font> Jor-El, by the authority of General Zod
喬艾爾，薩德將軍有令
surrender the Codex.
交出法典
<font color="#D900D9">(GROWLING)</font>
Easy, H'Raka.
慢慢來，哈拉卡
<font color="#D900D9">(H'RAKA GROANS)</font>
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> Did you find a world?
妳找到那星球了嗎？
- We have.<font color="#808080"> KELOR:</font>  Orbiting a main sequence yellow star just as you said it would.
找到了， 圍繞著一顆黃色恆星公轉 就像您說的那樣
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> A young star.
一顆年輕的新星
His cells will drink its radiation.
他的細胞會吸取那些輻射
It's a seemingly intelligent population.
看來住有高等智慧的居民
He'll be an outcast.
他會成為局外人
A freak.
像怪物
They'll kill him.
他們會殺了他
How?
怎麼殺？
He'll be a god to them.
他將如同神一般
<font color="#808080">LARA:</font> What if the ship doesn't make it?
要是太空船無法平安抵達？
He'll die out there
他會死在太空中
alone.
孤獨一人
I can't do it.
我做不到
I thought I could, but
我以為我可以，可是
- Lara. -  now that he's here
- 蘿拉 - 現在抱著他
Krypton is doomed.
氪利普頓星已經完了
It's his only chance now.
這是他唯一的機會
It's our people's only hope.
也是我們人民唯一的希望
<font color="#D900D9">(KELEX BLEEPING)</font>
What is it, Kelex?
怎麼了，姬莉絲？
<font color="#808080">KELEX:</font>  Five attack ships converging from the east.
有五艘攻擊船從東方而來
Citadel's defenses are being scanned and evaluated.
正在掃描和評估堡壘的防禦措施
I'll upload the Codex.
我來上傳生育法典
No, wait.
不，等等
Lara.
蘿拉
Just let me look at him.
讓我看看他
We'll never get to see him walk.
我們無法看到他跨出第一步
Never hear him say our names.
或聽到他喊我們
But out there amongst the stars
但在浩瀚宇宙，眾星之中
he will live.
他會活下去
<font color="#D900D9">(BABY COOING)</font>
Goodbye, my son.
再見，我的兒子
Our hopes and dreams travel with you.
我們的希望和夢想與你同行
Concentrate fire on the main doors.
集中火力在前門上
<font color="#808080">KELOR:</font>  Lady Lara.
蘿拉夫人
- The phantom drives are coming online. - Proceed to ignition.
- 幽靈驅動系統已連線  - 開始啟動
<font color="#808080">FAO RA:</font> General.
將軍
We have identified an engine ignition within the citadel.
我們偵測到堡壘中有引擎啟動
A launch.
他們要進行發射
Hold this platform, commander.
甲板保持戒備，指揮官
I know you stole the Codex, Jor-El.
我知道你偷了法典，喬艾爾
Surrender it and I'll let you live.
交出來我就饒你一命
This is a second chance for all of Krypton
這是克利普頓所有人重生的機會
not just the bloodlines you deem worthy.
且不只你覺得夠格的血脈
What have you done?
你做了什麼？
We've had a child, Zod.
我們生了孩子，薩德
A boy child.
一個男孩
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
克利普頓數世紀來首個自然誕生的孩子
And he will be free.
而且他會自由的成長
Free to forge his own destiny.
自由去開創他的未來
Heresy.
妖言惑眾
Destroy it.
摧毀它
<font color="#D900D9">(BOTH GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GROANING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(BLEEPING)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Lara listen to me.
蘿拉，聽我說
The Codex is Krypton's future.
生育法典是克利普頓的未來
Abort the launch.
不要發射
No!
不
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Your son, Lara
蘿拉，妳的兒子
where have you sent him?
妳把他送到哪去了？
<font color="#D900D9">(LARA SOBBING)</font>
His name
他的名字
is Kal
是凱艾爾
son of El.
艾爾之子
And he's beyond your reach.
你永遠都找不到他
Bring that ship down.
把那艘船打下來
Target locked.
目標鎖定
<font color="#808080">SOLDIER:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(OVER PA)</font>  Lay down your weapons.
放下武器
Your forces are surrounded.
你們的人馬被包圍了
<font color="#808080">LOR-EM:</font> General Zod
薩德將軍
for the crimes of murder and high treason
因為謀殺和叛亂罪
the Council has sentenced you and your fellow insurgents
和你共謀的黨羽，議會決定判你
to three hundred cycles of somatic reconditioning.
三百個循環的假死狀態太空流放
Do you have any last words?
有最後遺言嗎？
You won't kill us yourself!
你們不願自己動手殺我們
You wouldn't sully your hands! But you'll damn us
你們不想弄髒手
to a black hole for eternity!
卻寧可將我們永世打入黑洞
Jor-El was right.
喬艾爾說得沒錯
You're a pack of fools, every last one of you.
你們是群蠢蛋，每個都是
And you.
還有妳
You believe your son is safe?
妳以為妳兒子安全了嗎？
I will find him.
我會找到他
I will reclaim what you have taken from us.
我會奪回你們竊取的一切
I will find him.
我會找到他
I will find him, Lara.
我會找到他，蘿拉
I will find him!
我會找到他
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">KELOR:</font>  Lady Lara, shouldn't you find refuge?
蘿拉夫人，該去找庇護了
There is no refuge, Kelor.
已經無處可躲了，奇洛
Jor-El was right.
喬艾爾說得沒錯
This is the end.
末日來臨了
Make a better world than ours, Kal.
創造一個比這更好的世界，凱
(黛比蘇號)
<font color="#D900D9">(INDISTINCT DIALOGUE)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(CAGE WHINES)</font>
Watch it, dumb-ass!
小心點，蠢蛋
Keep your eyes open or you're gonna get squashed.
眼睛張大點，不然會被壓扁
Where the hell did they find you, greenhorn?
他們是從哪把你找來的，蠢新手？
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Let's get this trap in the air.
把這個籠子吊起來
<font color="#808080">HERALDSON:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON PA)</font>  Gentlemen, secure the deck.
各位，把設備綁好
We just got a distress call from a rig due west of us.
剛從西邊鑽井那裡收到求救訊號
Secure the deck.
把甲板上設備綁好
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(OVER RADIO)</font>  All civilian boats, stand clear.
所有平民船隻請勿靠近
The sub-sea valves failed and the rig is about to explode.
海底閥門失效，鑽井要爆炸了
<font color="#808080">HERALDSON:</font> Roger, Coast Guard. What about the men left inside?
收到，海岸防衛隊。那裡面的人怎麼辦？完畢
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font>  - Forget them. They're dead.  - Greenhorn
- 別管了，他們都死了 - 新來的
fetch me my binoculars.
把我的望遠鏡拿來
Greenhorn.
新來的
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> This is the last of the oxygen. I don't know how much longer we can hold out.
這些剩餘的氧氣 不知道還能撐多久
<font color="#808080">PILOT:</font>  This is Coast Guard 6510. We'll make one more pass then get out.
這是海岸防衛隊6510號 我們再巡一趟就要閃人了
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL CLAMORING)</font>
Wait, wait. I got some guys on the helipad.
等等，有人在直升機停機坪上
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Right here!
快來這裡
- Let's go! <font color="#808080">MAN 2:</font> - Let's go!
快走！快走！
<font color="#808080">PILOT:</font>  Get that last guy loaded.
把剩下那個人載走，我們得閃了
We have got to go.
我們該走了
<font color="#808080">MAN 1:</font> Hey, let's go. What are you doing?
快走了，你在幹嘛？
<font color="#808080">MAN 1:</font> Go! Go!
快走
<font color="#D900D9">(METAL CREAKING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">RAMPLING:</font>  when Kansas became a territory?
當堪薩斯成為領地？
<font color="#808080">RAMPLING:</font>  Clark.
克拉克
Are you listening, Clark?
你在聽嗎？克拉克
I asked if you could tell me who first　settled Kansas.
我問你誰先殖民到堪薩斯？
<font color="#D900D9">(GASPS)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(THUMPING)</font>
Are you all right, Clark?
你還好嗎？克拉克
<font color="#D900D9">(THUMPING LOUDLY)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(TICKING LOUDLY)</font>
<font color="#808080">RAMPLING:</font> Clark.
克拉克
Clark.
Clark!
克拉克
Clark, come out of there.
克拉克，快出來
Leave me alone.
別煩我
Clark, I have called your mother.
克拉克，我打給你媽媽了
Clark?
克拉克
<font color="#808080">RAMPLING:</font> Ah!
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> I'm here.
我來了
Clark, honey, it's Mom.
克拉克寶貝，是媽媽
Will you open the door?
把門打開好嗎？
<font color="#808080">BOY 1:</font> What's wrong with him? <font color="#808080">BOY 2:</font> He's such a freak.
- 他有什麼問題？ - 他真奇怪
<font color="#808080">BOY 3:</font> Crybaby.
愛哭鬼
<font color="#808080">GIRL 1:</font> His parents won't even let him play with other kids.
他爸媽不讓他跟其他小孩玩
<font color="#808080">GIRL 2:</font> I know.
我知道，真是個怪胎
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Sweetie.
乖兒子
How can I help you if you won't let me in?
你不讓我進去我怎麼幫你？
The world's too big, Mom.
世界太大了，媽媽
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Then make it small.
那就讓它變小
Just, um
你就
focus on my voice.
專心聽我的聲音
Pretend ifs an island out in the ocean.
假裝它是座小島，就在海上
Can you see it?
你看見了嗎？
I see it.
我看見了
Then swim towards it, honey.
朝它游過去，兒子
What's wrong with me, Mom?
我到底哪裡不對勁，媽？
Clark.
克拉克
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font>  Clark.
<font color="#D900D9">(WHALE TRUMPETING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(TRUMPETING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(SQUAWKING)</font>
<font color="#808080">WOMAN:</font> Did you get everything I need? <font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Yep.
東西你都買了嗎？
<font color="#808080">WOMAN:</font> Hold it, hold it.
等等，回來這裡
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CHATTERING)</font>
(校車)
<font color="#808080">PETE:</font> Hey, ass-wipe.
嘿，蠢蛋
What do you think? You see the game?
你覺得比賽如何？有去看嗎？
- Leave him alone, Pete. - What are you, his girlfriend?
- 別煩他，彼特 - 妳是他女朋友嗎？
I wanna hear what he has to say.
我想知道他的看法
Come on dick-splash.
說啊，屁蛋
<font color="#D900D9">(TIRE POPS AND KIDS SCREAM)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(TIRES SCREECHING AND HORN HONKING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(KIDS SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GASPING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(KIDS MURMURING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(PANTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">HELEN:</font>  My son was there.
我兒子在那裡
He was in the bus.
他在校車裡
- He saw what Clark did. <font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> - I know he did.
- 他看到克拉克做了什麼 - 我知道
- I'm sure what he thought he saw was  - Was an act of God, Jonathan.
- 他以為自己看到  - 那是神蹟，強納生
This was providence.
這是神蹟
<font color="#D900D9">(CHUCKLES)</font>
I think you're blowing it out of proportion.
我覺得妳也太誇張了
No, I'm not. Lana saw it too.
才沒有，拉娜也有看到
And the Fordham boy.
還有佛丹家的男孩
This isn't the first time
這也不是克拉克
Clark's done something like this.
第一次做出這樣的事
I just wanted to help.
我只是想要幫忙
I know you did, but we talked about this.
我知道，但我們談過這點
Right?
對嗎？
Right? We talked about this. You have
我們談過這個，你必須
Clark, you have to keep this side of yourself a secret.
你得把你的超能力當秘密守著
What was I supposed to do? Just let them die?
那我該怎麼做？看著他們死嗎？
Maybe.
或許吧
There's more at stake here than just our lives, Clark, or the lives of those around us.
不是只有我們自己，或我們周遭人的生活會有風險
When the world
當世人
When the world finds out what you can do it's gonna change everything. Our
當世人發現你的超能力，那會改變一切
Our beliefs, our notions of
我們的信仰，我們對
what it means to be human. Everything.
凡人所認知的定義，所有的一切
You saw how Pete's mom reacted, right?
你看到彼特媽媽的反應了
She was scared, Clark.
她很害怕，克拉克
Why?
為什麼？
People are afraid of what they don't understand.
人們總害怕自己不了解的事物
Is she right?
她是對的嗎？
Did God do this to me?
是神把我變成這樣的嗎？
Tell me.
告訴我
<font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> We found you in this.
我們在這裡面發現你
We were sure the government was gonna show up on our doorstep
我們確信政府很快就會來敲門
but no one ever came.
可是沒人找來
This was in that chamber with you.
這個也在太空艙內
I took it to a metallurgist at Kansas State.
我拿去給勘州大學的治金學家看
He said whatever it was made from didn't even
他說這種金屬材質
Didn't even exist on the periodic table.
甚至不存在元素週期表上
That's another way of saying
意思就是
that it's not from this world, Clark.
這不來自於我們世界，克拉克
And neither are you.
你也不是
You're the answer, son.
你就是答案，兒子
You're the answer to "Are we alone in the universe?"
人類不是宇宙唯一物種的解答
I don't wanna be.
我不想這樣
And I don't blame you, son.
我知道你不想，兒子
It'd be a huge burden for anyone to bear.
這對任何人來說都是沉重負擔
But you're not just anyone, Clark, and I have to believe that you were
但你不是凡人，克拉克，我必須相信你是
That you were sent here for a reason.
因為某些理由被送來
All these changes that you're going through, one day
你現在所經歷的一切變化
One day you're gonna think of them as a blessing. When that day comes you have to make a choice.
有天你會覺得是種福報，當那天來臨時，你得做出決定
A choice of whether to stand proud in front of the human race or not.
你要決定是否驕傲地聳立於世人面前
Can't I just keep pretending I'm your son?
我不能繼續當你兒子嗎？
You are my son.
你是我兒子啊
But somewhere out there you've
但在宇宙某處
You have another father too, who gave you another name.
你還有一位父親，給了你另個名字
And he sent you here for a reason, Clark.
他送你來此是有原因的，克拉克
And even if it takes you the rest of your life, you owe it to yourself
就算你必須窮盡一生
to find out what that reason is.
你也要為自己找出那理由
<font color="#808080">WOMAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(SINGING)</font>  Bound by wild desire
I fell into a ring of fire
<font color="#808080">MAN 1:</font> Wait a second. Aren't you here for the exercise?
等等，你不是該留下演習嗎？
<font color="#808080">MAN 2:</font> No, there was a change in the plans.
計劃改變了
Somebody found something strange on Ellesmere.
聽說有人在埃斯米爾島 找到奇怪的東西
- Aircom's making runs out there all week. <font color="#808080">MAN 1:</font> - That rat hole?
- 空軍總部整週往那裡送人 - 那個鬼地方？你別開玩笑了
- You gotta be kidding me. - I know. It's crazy.
很扯，對不對？
The Americans are there too, lots of them.
很多美國人也都來了
<font color="#808080">CHRISSY:</font> Anything else?<font color="#808080"> MAN 2:</font> They're calling it an anomalous object.
- 還要什麼嗎？ - 他們稱它為「異常物體」 不知什麼意思
- Whatever that means. - Back off, Ludlow. I'm serious.
別煩我，盧洛，我是認真的
<font color="#808080">LUDLOW:</font> - Oh, come on, Chrissy. - Knock it off.
- 別這樣，克莉絲 - 別鬧了
- Sit down. <font color="#808080">CHRISSY:</font> - Let me go.
- 坐下 - 放開我
Hey. Leave her alone, man.
別煩她，老兄
<font color="#D900D9">(GLASS SHATTERS)</font>
Or what, tough guy?
不然怎樣，猛男？
Or I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
不然我就得請你離開
I think I'll probably just leave when I'm good and ready.
等大爺我高興了我才會走
<font color="#D900D9">(MEN LAUGHING)</font>
Oh, there he is.
他生氣了
<font color="#808080">CHRISSY:</font> It's not worth it, sweetie.
不值得
<font color="#808080">LUDLOW:</font> Hey, asshole, don't forget your tip.
混蛋，別忘了你的小費
<font color="#D900D9">(MEN LAUGHING)</font>
Strike.
打擊出局
<font color="#D900D9">(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)</font>
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Thanks.
謝謝
Hi.
嗨
Miss Lane. How you doing?
蓮恩小姐，妳好嗎？
- Good. - Jed Eubanks, Arctic Cargo.
- 很好 - 杰德尤班克斯，極地貨運航空
How far to the station?
這裡離基地多遠？
- Camp's just over the rise. I'll walk you over. - Great.
- 營區就在小丘那裡，我陪妳走過去 -很好
Joe can take your bags. Joe.
喬會幫妳提行李，喬
Help her out.
來幫她
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Careful with those. They're heavy.
小心點，很重的
I gotta confess, Miss Lane
我得承認，蓮恩小姐
I'm not a fan of the Daily Planet.
我不太喜歡「星球日報」
But those pieces you wrote when you were embedded with the 1st Division were
但妳採訪第一師時所寫的文章
Well, they were pretty impressive.
那些文章很令人驚艷
Well, what can I say? I get writer's block if I'm not wearing a flak jacket.
該怎麼說呢？若沒穿上防彈衣我啥都寫不出來
<font color="#D900D9">(JED CHUCKLES)</font>
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font>  Miss Lane.
蓮恩小姐
I'm Colonel Hardy, U.S. Northcom.
我是哈帝上校，美國北方司令部
Dr. Emil Hamilton from DARPA.
這是國防先進研究計劃局的漢米頓博士
- You're early. - Hi.
妳來早了
We were expecting you tomorrow.
本來安排妳明天到
Which is why I showed up today.
所以我才今天來
Look, let's get one thing straight, guys, okay?
我們把話講明
The only reason I'm here is because we're on Canadian soil
我能來的唯一原因，是因為我們在加拿大領土
and the appellate court overruled your injunction to keep me away.
所以上訴法院駁回，你們對我申請的禁制令
So if we're done measuring dicks
如果我們比完大小
can you have your people show me what you found?
可以帶我參觀你們的發現嗎？
<font color="#808080">SEKOWSKY:</font>  NASA's EOS satellites pinged the anomaly first.
太空總署的地球觀測衛星，以聲波探測到異物
The ice shelf plays hell on the echo soundings.
冰層讓聲波反射難以偵測
But there's something there.
但是下面肯定有東西
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>Soviet-era?  A submarine, maybe?
或許是蘇聯時期的潛水艇？
Doubtful. That's 300 meters.
不太可能，那有三百米長
Considerably larger than anything we know they built back then.
比當時的船艦大上許多
But herds the spooky pan.
但奇怪的部分在這裡
The ice surrounding the object
圍繞物體的冰
it's nearly twenty thousand years old.
年代將近有兩萬年之久
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font>  Miss Lane?
蓮恩小姐
Try not to wander.
別亂跑
Temperatures drop to minus 40 at night around here.
晚上最低溫可達零下四十度
Wouldn't find your body till after spring.
不然屍體得等到春天才找得到
And there you go.
到了
What if I need to tinkle?
要是我要上小號呢？
There's a bucket in the corner.
角落有個水桶
<font color="#D900D9">(CAMERA CLICKING)</font>
Where the hell are you going?
你想上哪去？
<font color="#D900D9">(WHIRRING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(INDISTINCT CHATTER)</font>
Hello?
有人嗎？
<font color="#D900D9">(INDISTINCT CHATTER)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(LOIS GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(CLARK GRUNTS)</font>
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font> It's all right, it's all right, it's all right. It's all right.
沒事，沒事，沒事了
<font color="#D900D9">(PANTING)</font>
You're hemorrhaging internally
妳正在內出血
and if I don't cauterize this bleed
如果我不替妳燒灼止血的話
How can ?
你要怎麼
I can do things that other people can't.
我可以做常人做不到的事
Now hold my hand.
抓住我的手
This is gonna hurt.
會很痛
<font color="#D900D9">(SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(COMPUTER BEEPING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(RUMBLING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALARM WAILING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  What Colonel Hardy and his team surmised was a Soviet-era submarine.
哈帝上校和他同仁，認為是前蘇聯潛水艇的物體
was actually something much more exotic.
其實來自更遙遠的地方
An isotope analysis of the surrounding ice bores suggests that an object
同位素分析周圍鑿冰的結果指出
had been trapped in the glacier for over 18,000 years.
這船艦已被困在冰河中，長達一萬八千年之久
As for my rescuer?
至於我的救命恩人
He disappeared during the object's departure,.
他在船艦升空時消失了
A background check revealed that his work history
背景調查顯示，他的工作經歷
and identity had been falsified.
和身份都是偽造的
The questions raised by my rescuer's existence
我救命恩人的存在引出很多問題
are frightening to contemplate. but I also know what I saw.
這些疑題令人畏懼，但我確知自己看見了什麼
"And I have arrived at the inescapable conclusion
我因此得出不可避諱的結論
that the object and its occupant
這艘船艦及其組員
did not originate on Earth."
並非來自地球
I can't print this, Lois. You might have hallucinated half of it.
我不能刊登，露意絲，有一半可能出自妳的幻覺
What about the contractors who corroborated
可是民間承包商證實了我的說法
-  my story? - The Pentagon is denying that there was a ship.
五角大廈否認這艘船的存在
Of course they are. They're supposed to.
那是當然，他們只會否認
It's the Pentagon.
他們是五角大廈
Perry, it's me we're talking about. I'm a Pulitzer Prize-winning reporter.
派瑞，我可是得過普立茲新聞獎
Then act like it.
那就更得像樣一點
- Print it or I walk. - You can't.
- 你不登我就辭職 -妳不能辭職
You're under contract.
妳有合約在身
<font color="#D900D9">(SIGHS)</font>
I'm not running a story about aliens walking among us.
我不會刊登 「外星人就在你身邊」這種文章
<font color="#D900D9">(PERRY SIGHS)</font>
Never gonna happen.
想都別想
That's a Scotch, straight-up, for the lady.
給小姐的威士忌
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> I'm sending you the article.
我把原文寄給你
My editor won't print it, but if it leaked online
我的總編不肯登，但如果不小心到網路上
Got it.
我懂了
But didn't you once describe my site
但妳不是曾說，我的網站是
as a creeping cancer of falsehoods?
「如毒瘤般蔓延的謊言中心」？
I stand by my words, Woodburn, but I want this story
我仍這麼認為，伍伯恩
-  out there. - Why?
- 但我希望文章被發佈  - 為什麼？
Because I want my mystery man to know I know the truth.
因為我希望我的神祕男子知道，我知道實情
<font color="#808080">COMPUTER:</font>  Recursive diagnostics complete,.
遞歸診斷完成
Guiding presence authenticated.
駕駛身份確認
All systems operational.
所有系統運作正常
To see you standing there having grown into an adult
看你長大成人站在我面前
If only Lara could have witnessed this.
要是蘿拉能看到就好了
Who are you?
你是誰？
I am your father, Kal.
我是你父親，凱
Or at least a shadow of him.
或者說是他的投影
His consciousness.
他的有知意識
My name was Jor-El.
我的名字是喬艾爾
And Kal?
那凱呢？
That's my name.
那是我的名字
Kal-El. It is.
凱艾爾，沒錯
I have so many questions.
我有好多問題
Where do I come from?
我從哪裡來？
Why did you send me here?
你為何把我送來地球？
You came from Krypton.
你來自氪利普頓星
A world with a much harsher environment than Earths.
那裡的環境比地球惡劣許多
Long ago
很久以前
in an era of expansion
在開拓時期
our race spread out through the stars
我們的種族散佈在群星間
seeking new worlds to settle upon.
找尋適合定居的新世界
This scout ship was one of thousands launched into the void.
有上千艘像這樣的偵察艦，被發射到太空中
We built outposts on other planets
我們在別的行星上建立前哨站
musing great machines to reshape environments to our needs.
用先進機器重塑當地環境，以符合我們需求
For 100,000 years, our civilization flourished
我們的文明繁盛了十萬年
accomplishing wonders.
創造許多奇蹟
What happened?
然後怎麼了？
Artificial population control was established.
我們施行人工生育控制
The outposts on space exploration were abandoned.
太空探索的前哨站被棄置
We exhausted our natural resources.
我們用盡天然資源
As a result, our planet's core became unstable.
行星的核心因此變得不穩定
Eventually, our military leader
最終我們的軍事領袖
General Zod, attempted a coup.
薩德將軍，試圖發動政變
But by then it was too late.
但為時已晚
Your mother and I foresaw the coming calamity
你母親和我預見即將來臨的災難
and we took certain steps to ensure your survival.
我們採取措施以確保你的存活
This is a genesis chamber.
這是創始室
All Kryptonians were conceived in chambers such as this.
所有克利普頓人都在創始室裡孕育
Every child was designed to fulfill a pre-determined role in our society
每個孩子都被設計成 符合某個社會使命的預定角色
as a worker
成為勞工
a warrior, a leader and so on.
戰士，或領袖之類的
Your mother and I believed Krypton lost something precious.
你母親和我認為克利普頓，已失去最珍貴的東西
The element of choice, of chance.
選擇和機會的元素
What if a child dreamed of becoming something
如果一個孩子想成為
mother than what society had intended for him or her?
為他設計以外的角色呢？
What if a child aspired to something greater?
如果孩子想要有更高的成就呢？
You were the embodiment of that belief, Kal.
你就是那個理念的實踐
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
氪利普頓星數世紀來，第一個自然產下的孩子
That's why we risked so much to save you.
因此我們冒如此大險確保你安全
Why didn't you come with me?
你們為何不跟我一起走？
We couldn't, Kal.
我們不行，凱
No matter how much we wanted to.
不管我們有多想
No matter how much we loved you.
不管我們有多愛你
Your mother, Lara, and I
你母親蘿拉和我
were a product of the failures of our world as much as Zod was
還有薩德都是我們失敗世界的產物
tied to its fate.
必須和它同進退
- So I'm alone. - No.
- 所以我孤獨一人 - 不
You're as much a child of Earth now as you are of Krypton.
你現在是地球的子民，就如同你是克利普頓子民
You can embody the best of both worlds.
你是集兩個世界之大成的體現
A dream your mother and I dedicated our lives to preserve.
你母親和我用生命達成了這夢想
The people of Earth are different from us, it's true.
地球人和我們的確不同，這是事實
But, ultimately, I believe that's a good thing.
但最終，我認為這是好事
They won't necessarily make the same mistakes we did.
他們不見得會犯下我們的錯誤
Not if you guide them, Kal.
如果有你指引就不會
Not if you give them hope.
如果有你帶給他們希望
That's what this symbol means.
這就是這個符號的含意
The symbol of the house of El means hope.
艾爾家的符號意謂著希望
Embodied within that hope is the fundamental belief
在希望中體現的是人基本的信念：
in the potential of every person to be a force for good.
每個人都有潛力成為善良的力量
That's what you can bring them.
這是你能帶給他們的
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font>  Why am I so different from them?
為何我與他們如此不同？
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font>  Earth's sun is younger and brighter than Krypton's was.
地球的太陽 比氪利普頓星的更年輕更明亮
Your cells have drunken its radiation
你的細胞吸取太陽的輻射
strengthening your muscles, your skin, your senses.
強化了你的肌肉、皮膚和感覺
Earth's gravity is weaker, yet its atmosphere is more nourishing.
地球的重力較弱 但大氣層卻養分充足
You've grown stronger here than I ever could have imagined.
你長得比我想像中更為強壯
The only way to know how strong
唯有透過試探自己的極限
is to keep testing your limits.
才會知道你到底有多強壯
<font color="#D900D9">(LAUGHS)</font>
Whoa!
不
<font color="#D900D9">(GROANING)</font>
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font>  You will give the people of Earth an ideal lo strive towards.
你會帶給地球人一個努力的目標
They'll race behind you.
他們會在你身後追逐
They will stumble.
他們會跌倒
They will fall.
他們會失敗
But In time
但假以時日
they will join you in the sun, Kal.
他們會追隨你的領導，凱
In time
假以時日
you will help them accomplish wonders.
你會幫助他們達成奇蹟
<font color="#D900D9">(RUMBLING)</font>
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  How do you find someone who has spent a lifetime covering his tracks?
要如何找到一個，一輩子都在掩蓋蹤跡的人
You start with the urban legends  that have sprung up in his wake.  <font color="#808080">JED:</font> That's Joe.
- 就從他身後流傳的傳奇找起   -這是喬
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  The friends of a friend who have seen him.  <font color="#808080">CHRISSY:</font> - He worked here.
-  那些聲稱看過他的朋友的朋友   -他在這裡工作過
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  For some he was a guardian angel. For others, a cipher
對某些人而言，他是守護天使
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font>  Well, I was saying we were  a ghost who never quite fit in
對其他人，則是個謎團
coming towards the oil rig.
一個不曾融入的鬼魂
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  As you work your way back in time, the stories form a pattern.
隨著時光追溯，故事開始出現模式
I'm looking for a Pete Ross. Do you know him?
我在找彼特羅斯，你認識嗎？
Yeah, he works at the IHOP. If you go down the road
認識，他在鬆餅屋工作，妳往這邊走
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Pete Ross?
彼特羅斯？
I'd like to talk to you about an accident when you were younger.
我想跟你談你小時候發生的意外
A school bus that went into the river.
那個校車墜河事件
(肯特家)
<font color="#D900D9">(DOG BARKING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Dusty. Shh-shh-shh.
達斯提
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Mrs. Kent?
肯特太太
I'm Lois Lane. I'm from the  Daily Planet.
我是「星球日報」的露意絲蓮恩
<font color="#D900D9">(DOG BARKING)</font>
Quiet.
安靜
I'm from the Daily Planet and I'd like to talk to you about your son.
我是「星球日報」的記者，我想跟妳談談妳兒子
(強納生肯特 摯愛的丈夫和慈父)
<font color="#D900D9">(WIND BLOWING)</font>
I figured if I turned over enough stones you'd eventually find me.
我想只要我挖得夠深，你遲早會出面見我
Where are you from? What are you doing here?
你來自哪裡？在這裡幹嘛？
Let me tell your story.
讓我報導你的故事
What if I don't want my story told?
要是我不希望我的故事曝光呢？
It's going to come out eventually.
故事遲早都會曝光
Somebody's going to get a photograph or figure out where you live.
有人會拍到照片或發現你的住處
Then I'll disappear again.
那我就會再度消失
The only way you could disappear is to stop helping people altogether
你唯一能永久消失的辦法，就是停止幫助別人
and I sense that's not an option for you.
但我感覺你不會選擇如此
My father believed that if the world found out who I really was
我父親深信 如果世界發現我的真實身份
they'd reject me out of fear.
他們會因為恐懼而排斥我
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font>  I'm tired of safe.
我厭倦了隱姓埋名
I just wanna do something useful with my life.
我想用我的人生做些有用的事
So farming, feeding people. That's not useful?
那種田，餵飽人們不夠有用嗎？
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font> I didn't say that.
我沒那麼說
<font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> Our family's been farming for five generations.
我們家族已五代務農，克拉克
Your family, not mine.
那是你的家族，不是我的
I don't even know why I'm listening to you. You're not my dad.
我不知道為何要聽你的。你又不是我爸
You're just some guy who found me in a field.
你只是在田裡找到我
Clark.
克拉克
It's all right, Martha.
沒關係，瑪莎
He's right. Clark has a point.
他說得對，克拉克講得也有道理
We're not your parents.
我們不是你的父母
But we've been doing the best we can.
但我們盡力做到最好
And we've been making this up as we go along, so maybe
我們一邊撫養你一邊學習，所以或許
Maybe our best isn't good enough anymore.
我們的最好已經不夠了
Look, Dad
聽著，爸
Hold on.
等等
<font color="#D900D9">(WIND WHISTLING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(THUNDER RUMBLING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> Go for the overpass.
快去陸橋哪裡
Go for the overpass!
快去陸橋那裡
Take cover! Take cover!
找掩護，找掩護
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Over there. Just follow them. <font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> Take cover.
找掩護
<font color="#808080">WOMAN:</font> She's stuck.
她卡住了
Hank's still in the car.
漢克還在車裡
Hank's in the car.
漢克在車裡
- I'll get him, I'll get him. <font color="#808080">JONATHAN:</font> - No, no.
- 我去救牠，我去救牠 - 不不
Get your mom to the overpass.
帶你媽去橋下躲著
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CLAMORING)</font>
Hank! Hank! Come!
漢克，漢克
Jonathan! - Mom, ifs okay.
- 不，媽，沒關係 - 強納生
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
- Jonathan! - Mom, stay here.
- 強納生 - 媽，留在這裡
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
Dad!
爸
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font>  I let my father die because I trusted him.
我讓我爸死去，因為我相信牠
Because he was convinced that I had to wait.
因為他堅信我必須等待
That the world was not ready.
因為世界還沒準備好
What do you think?
那你怎麼覺得？
<font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> You better watch out, Lois.
妳最好皮繃緊點，露意絲
Hey, Perry's gunning for you.
派瑞要找妳開刀
He knows you're Woodburn's anonymous source and cannot wait to rip you a new one.
他知道妳把文章給伍伯恩，他等不及要修理妳
Oh, look at her. Ha, ha, ha.
你看他
<font color="#D900D9">(KNOCKING)</font>
I told you not to run with this, and what do you do?
我叫妳別亂來，結果妳做了什麼？
You let Woodburn just shotgun it all over the Internet.
妳讓伍伯恩在網路上大登特登
Now the publishers want me to sue you.
現在報紙的出版商要我告妳
Well, if it makes a difference, I'm dropping it.
如果你會覺得好過點，我不再追這個故事了
Whoa, just like that?
就那麼簡單嗎？
Yep.
對
What happened to your leads?
妳的線索怎麼了？
They didn't pan out. The story is smoke.
沒結果，故事只是煙幕彈
Or it didn't get the traction you hoped?
又或許是沒達到妳想要的效果
Two weeks leave no pay, that's your penance.
無薪假兩週，那是妳的懲戒
You try something like this again
如果再耍一次這種花招
-  you're done here. - Fine.
- 妳就玩完了 - 好
Let's make it three weeks since you're so willing to agree.
既然妳這麼願意配合，那就三週吧
- Perry. - No, no. Don't. Don't.
- 派瑞 - 不，不要
I believe you saw something, Lois.
我相信妳有看到什麼
But not for a moment do I believe that your leads just went cold.
但我一點也不相信，妳沒追到線索
So whatever your reasons are for dropping it
所以不管妳放棄的理由是什麼
I think you're doing the right thing.
我都認為是正確的決定
Why?
為什麼？
Can you imagine how people on this planet would react
妳能想像人類會如何反應嗎？
if they knew there was someone like this out there?
如果他們知道世上有此等人物
<font color="#D900D9">(VEHICLE APPROACHING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(DOOR CLOSES)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(DOG BARKS)</font>
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Go get him.
快去迎接他
<font color="#D900D9">(DOG BARKING)</font>
Well, look at you.
瞧瞧你
<font color="#D900D9">(BOTH LAUGHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> A reporter came by here.
有個記者來過
She's a friend. Don't worry.
她是我朋友，別擔心
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Oh.
是喔
Mom.
媽
- Heh, heh, heh. - What?
怎麼了？
- I found them. - Who?
-  我找到他們了  -誰？
My parents.
我的父母
My People.
我的族人
I know where I come from now.
我知道我來自哪裡了
Wow.
天啊
That's wonderful.
那太棒了
I'm so happy for you, Clark.
我真替你高興，克拉克
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font> - What? - It's nothing.
-  怎麼了？  -  沒什麼
When you were a baby I used to lay by your crib at night
當你還是寶寶時 我晚上常躺在你的小床邊
listening to you breathe.
聽你的呼吸
It was hard for you.
那對你來說很艱難
You struggled.
你努力掙扎
And I worried all the time.
我總是很擔心
You worried the truth would come out.
妳擔心事實會曝光
No.
不
The truth about you is beautiful.
關於你的事實是美麗的
We saw that the moment we laid eyes on you.
我們第一眼看你時就知道了
We knew that one day, the whole world would see that.
我們知道總有一天，這世界也會看到這點
I'm just
我只是
I'm worried they'll take you away from me.
我擔心他們會把你帶走
<font color="#D900D9">(CLARK CHUCKLES)</font>
I'm not going anywhere, Mom.
我哪也不會去，媽媽
I promise.
我保證
(北美防空司令部，北方指揮中心)
<font color="#808080">HAMILTON:</font> General Swanwick, sir.
史旺威克將軍
What am I looking at, doc? Comet? Asteroid?
我們看的是什麼，博士 彗星？小行星？
Comets don't make course corrections, general.
彗星不會矯正路線，將軍
Wanted you to see this before some amateur with a telescope creates a worldwide panic.
在業餘天文家用望遠鏡看到而引起恐慌前，想先給你看
The ship appears to have inserted itself into a lunar synchronous orbit
這艘太空船似乎自行進入，與月球等速運轉的軌道
though I have no idea why.
但我不知道為什麼
Have you tried  communicating with it?
有試著與他們溝通嗎？
Well, they haven't responded as of yet.
他們還沒回覆
I'm just speculating, but I think whoever's at the helm of that thing
我只是在猜測，我猜那艘船的人
is looking to make a dramatic entrance.
想要來個戲劇化的登場
<font color="#D900D9">(BEEPING)</font>
(提醒)
(更換墨水)
Anybody know where we keep the toner?
有人知道墨水匣在哪嗎？
- What's going on? - It's all over the news.
- 怎麼回事？ - 新聞全在報導
You gotta see this.
妳得來看看
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL MURMURING)</font>
(發現不明飛行物體 民眾由地面拍攝)
<font color="#D900D9">(FOOTBALL ANNOUNCER SPEAKING ON TV)</font>
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Clark.
克拉克
Yeah?
怎麼了？
Coming.
我來了
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON TV)</font>  This is a breaking news. An unidentified
(新聞快報)
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(DISTORTION NOISE ON TV)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON TV)</font>  You are not alone.
你們不是唯一
You are not alone.
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON TV)</font>  You are not alone.
你們不是唯一
<font color="#D900D9">(ZOD SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ON TV)</font>
<font color="#808080">JENNY:</font> It's coming in on the RSS feeds.
這是從RSS閱讀器傳來的
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON TV)</font>  You are not alone.
It's on my phone too.
連我手機上也有
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font>  My name is General Zod.
我的名字是薩德將軍
I come from a world far from yours.
我來自一個遙遠的世界
I have journeyed across an ocean of stars to reach you.
我穿越漫漫星海來接觸你們
For some time, your world has sheltered one of my citizens.
長久以來，你們窩藏一個我族子民
I request that you return this individual
我要求你們將他交回
to my custody.
給我方管束
For reasons unknown, he has chosen to keep his existence
因不明原因，他隱藏真實身份
a secret from you.
不讓你們知道
He will have made efforts to blend in.
他努力的融入你們
He will look like you.
他看起來會像你們一樣
But he is not one of you.
但他絕非你們的同類
To those of you who may know of his current location
知道他現今所在位置的人
the fate of your planet
你們星球的命運
rests in your hands.
掌握在你們手中
To Kai-El, I say this:
給凱艾爾，你聽好
Surrender within 24 hours
限你二十四小時內投降
or watch this world suffer the consequences..
否則就眼睜睜看這世界受苦
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE MURMURING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(FIRE TRUCK SIREN WAILING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(KETTLE WHISTLING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON TV)</font>  We hardly know anything about him, isn't that right?
我們對他一無所知，對嗎？
<font color="#808080">WOODBURN:</font>  If he truly means us no harm
如果他不想傷害我們
he'll turn himself in and face the consequences.
他就會去跟他族人自首，然後面對後果
then maybe we should. And if he won't do that
如果他不去，或許該由我們動手
The Daily Planet's Lois Lane knows who this guy is. She's
「星球日報」的露意絲蓮恩 知道他是誰
the one we should be questioning.
我想大家應該去問她
<font color="#D900D9">(PHONE RINGING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font>  Hold on. You're saying Lois Lane   - Hello?
-等等，你是說露意絲蓮恩  -  喂
Are you watching this crap? Been running all morning.
妳在看電視嗎？整早都在播這個
For once I agree with Woodburn. Have you seen him?
這是我首次贊同伍伯恩，妳有見過他嗎？
- Do you know where he is?  - No. Even if I did, I wouldn't say.
- 知道他在哪嗎？ - 不知道，就算知道也不會說
The entire world is being threatened here.
全世界現在都受到威脅
This is not time for you to fall back on journalistic integrity.
現在不是考慮新聞道德的時候
This is serious, Lois.
事情很嚴重，露意絲
The FBI is here. They're throwing around words like "treason."
FBI跑來辦公室，他們用了叛國之類的字眼
I gotta go.
我得走了
<font color="#D900D9">(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(TIRES SCREECHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">AGENT:</font> FBI. Hands up.
FBI，把手舉起來
Drop the bag. Now.
立刻把包包放下
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(ON RADIO)</font> Regarding the visitors themselves we know
我們對外星訪客的了解非常少
the visitors do not represent a threat very little. According to government officials
根據受訪的政府官員，外星訪客的訊息雖然聽來駭人
despite the ominous tone of their message.
但並無提出實質威脅
Then of course there's the question on everyone's mind:
當然大家心裡想的是：
"Who is this Kai-El person? Does he actually exist?"
這個凱艾爾到底是誰？ 他真的存在嗎？
"How could he have remained hidden from us for so long?"
他如何能不著痕跡存在世間如此之久？
<font color="#808080">KEN:</font> Come on, Kent.
來啊，肯特
Come on. Fight back.
來啊，回擊
Get up, Kent.
起來，肯特
<font color="#D900D9">(KEN LAUGHS)</font>
So is that it?
就這樣嗎？
Is that all you've got?
你只有這點能耐？
Come on, Kent.
來啊，肯特
Come on!
來啊
Did they hurl you?
他們有弄傷你嗎？
You know they can't.
你明知他們傷不了我
That's not what I meant. I meant, are you all right?
我不是那個意思，我是問你還好嗎？
I wanted to hit that kid. I wanted to hit him bad.
我想打那小子，我好想打他
I know you did. I mean
我知道你想，我是說
part of me even wanted you to, but then what?
某部分的我也希望你回手，但然後呢？
Make you feel any better?
你會感覺好些嗎？
You just have to decide what kind of man you want to grow up to be, Clark.
你必須決定你長大想成為哪種人，克拉克
Because whoever that man is, good character or bad, he's
不管那個人是好人還是壞人
He's gonna change the world.
他都會改變這個世界
<font color="#808080">FATHER LEONE:</font>  What's on your mind?
你在想什麼？
I don't know where to start.
我不知道從何說起
Wherever you want.
從哪說起都行
That ship that appeared last night.
昨晚出現的太空船
I'm the one they're looking for.
我就是他們要找的人
<font color="#D900D9">(GULPS)</font>
Do you know
你知道
why they want you?
他們為何要找你？
No. But this General Zod
不知道，但這個薩德將軍
even if I surrender, there's no guarantee he'll keep his word, but
就算我自首，也不能保證他會遵守承諾
if there's a chance I can save Earth by turning myself in
但如果我的自首能拯救地球
shouldn't I take it?
難道我不該這麼做嗎？
What does your gut tell you?
你的直覺怎麼說？
Zod can't be trusted.
不能信任薩德
The problem is
問題是
I'm not sure the people of Earth can be either.
我也不知道地球人能不能信任
<font color="#808080">LEONE:</font> Sometimes you have to take a leap of faith first.
有時你得先讓自己有信仰
The trust part comes later.
之後才能建立信任
<font color="#D900D9">(INDISTINCT CHATTER)</font>
All right. You've got our attention.
好了，我們已經注意到你了
What is it you want?
你想要幹嘛？
I would like to speak to Lois Lane.
我想跟露意絲蓮恩談話
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> What makes you think she's here?
你為何覺得她在這裡？
Don't play games with me, general.
別跟我玩遊戲，將軍
I'll surrender, but only if you guarantee Lois's freedom.
我會自首，但你必須保障露意絲的自由
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font>  Why are you surrendering to Zod?
你為何要向薩德自首？
I'm surrendering to mankind. There's a difference.
我是向人類投降，這兩者有所不同
You let them handcuff you?
你讓他們給你上手銬？
Wouldn't be much of a surrender if I resisted.
如果我抗拒，這算哪門子的自首
And if it makes them feel more secure
而且這樣讓他們覺得更安全
then all the better for it.
這樣更好
What's the S stand for?
S是什麼意思？
<font color="#D900D9">(SIGHS)</font>
It's not an S.
這個不是S
On my world it means hope.
在我的世界這代表希望
Well, here, it's an S.
在這裡就是個字母
How about
不如就叫
Super
超
<font color="#808080">HAMILTON:</font> Sir?
先生
- Hi, my name is Dr. E  <font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> - Emil Hamilton.
-  你好，我是   -  漢米頓博士
I know, I can see your ID tag in your breast pocket.
我知道，我可以看到你胸前口袋裡的名牌
Along with a half-eaten roll of Lifesavers.
口袋裡還有半條薄荷糖
I can also see the soldiers in the next room
我還可以看到隔壁的一班士兵
preparing that tranquilizing agent of yours.
他們在準備麻醉劑
You won't need it.
你不會需要它
Sir, you can't expect us to not take precautions.
先生，你不能期望我們不採取防護措施
You could be carrying some kind of alien pathogen.
你可能帶有外星病原體
Been here for 33 years, doctor.
我住這裡已經33年了，博士
- Haven't infected anyone yet. - That you know of.
- 我還沒傳染給任何人 - 據你所知是沒有
We have legitimate security concerns.
我們有合理的安全考量
You revealed your identity to Miss Lane over there.
你向蓮恩小姐揭露了自己的身份
Why won't you do the same with us?
為何不向我們這麼做？
Let's put our cards on the table here, general.
我們攤牌吧，將軍
You're scared because you can't control me.
你畏懼我，因為你不能控制我
You don't, and you never will.
你是不能，而且永遠不能
But that doesn't' mean I'm your enemy.
但那不代表我是你敵人
Then who is?
那誰才是？
Zod?
薩德嗎？
That's what I'm worried about.
那是我所擔心的事
Be that as it may
即便如此
I've been given orders to hand you over to him.
我收到命令要把你移交給他
Do what you have to do, general.
做你必須做的事，將軍
Thank you.
謝謝妳
For what?
為了什麼？
For believing in me.
因為妳相信我
Didn't make much difference in the end.
到頭來還不是一樣
It did to me.
對我有所不同
<font color="#D900D9">(SONIC BOOM)</font>
They're coming.
他們來了
You should leave now.
妳該走了
Go, Lois.
走吧，露意絲
<font color="#808080">FAORA:</font> Kal-El.
凱艾爾
I'm sub-commander Faora-UI.
我是副指揮官費歐拉奧爾
On behalf of General Zod, I extend you his greetings.
我代表薩德將軍表達他的歡迎
- Are you the ranking officer here? - I am.
- 你是這裡帶頭的軍官嗎？ - 我是
General Zod would like this woman
薩德將軍想要這個女人
to accompany me.
跟我一起走
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> You asked for the alien.
你本來只要求要外星人
You didn't say anything about one of our own.
沒有提到我們的人
Shall I tell the general you're unwilling to comply?
我該告訴將軍你不願意配合嗎？
I don't care what you tell him.
我不在乎妳跟他怎麼說
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> It's all right.
沒關係
I'll go.
我願意去
The atmospheric composition on our ship is not compatible with humans.
我們船上的大氣組成不適合人類
You need to wear a breather beyond this point.
進去之後妳得配帶呼吸器
Kal-El.
凱艾爾
You have no idea how long we've been searching for you.
你不知道我們找了你多久
I take it you're Zod?
我猜你就是薩德？
General Zod. Our commander.
薩德將軍，我們的指揮官
It's all right, Faora.
沒關係，費歐拉
We can forgive Kal any lapses in decorum.
我們可以原諒凱的禮數不周
He's a stranger to our ways.
他對我們的風俗習慣不熟悉
This should be cause for celebration
我們該為團圓而慶祝
<font color="#808080"><font color="#808080">ZOD: </font> Not conflict.
不是對峙
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> Unh. <font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Not conflict.
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> I
我
feel strange.
感覺好奇怪
<font color="#D900D9">(SUPERMAN COUGHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> Weak.
好虛弱
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> What's happening to him?
他怎麼了？
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> He's rejecting our ship's atmospherics.
他對船上的大氣產生排斥
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Clark.
克拉克
You've spent a lifetime adapting to Earth's ecology
你花了一輩子適應地球的生態
but never adapted to ours.
但從來沒適應過我們的
Help him.
幫幫他
I can't.
不行
- Whatever's happening has to run its course. <font color="#808080"> LOIS:</font> - Clark.
-  要讓他的身體自行戰勝環境  -  克拉克
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
Help him.
幫幫他
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Hello, Kal.
嗨，凱
Or do you prefer Clark?
還是你喜歡叫你克拉克？
That's the name they gave you.
那是他們給你的名字
Isn't it?
對嗎？
I was Krypton's military leader
我以前是氪利普頓星的軍事領袖
your father our foremost scientist.
你父親則是首席科學家
The only thing we agreed on
我們唯一意見相同的
was that Krypton was dying.
就是克利普頓將走向滅亡
In return for my effortsto protect our civilization and save our planet
雖然我努力起義想保存文明，和拯救我們星球
I and my fellow officers were sentenced to the Phantom Zone.
我和手下卻被流放幽靈黑洞區
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font>  And then the destruction of our world
在那裡，我們世界的毀滅
freed us.
卻釋放了我們
We were adrift, destined to float
我們漂流著
amongst the ruins of our planet
註定和我們星球的碎片一起浮沉
until we starved.
直至餓死
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font>  How did you find your way to Earth?
你是如何取道地球的？
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font>  We managed to retrofit the phantom projector into a hyperdrive.
我們改造幽靈黑洞監獄船，讓它能做超時空旅行
Your father made a similar modification to the craft that brought you here.
你父親在你乘坐的太空船上，也做了類似的改造
And so the instrument of our damnation
因此禁錮我們的監獄
became our salvation.
也成了我們的救贖
We sought out the old colonial outposts
我們在舊殖民前哨站間
looking for signs of life.
尋找生命跡象
But all we found was death.
但我們只找到死亡
Cut off from Krypton, these outposts
被克利普頓棄置後
withered and died long ago.
這些基地早已衰亡
We salvaged what we could
我們搜刮可用物資
armor, weapons
盔甲，武器
even a world engine.
還有一具太空世界引擎
For 33 years we prepared
33年來我們努力準備
until finally we detected a distress beacon
直到我們終於偵測到求救訊號
which you triggered
那是你觸發的
when you accessed the ancient scout ship.
當你啟動那艘古老偵察艦
You led us here, Kal.
你將我們引來此處，凱
Now it's within your power to save what remains of your race.
現在你有能力拯救你殘存的族人
On Krypton
在氪利普頓星
the genetic template for every being yet to be born
尚未出生的人的基因樣板
is encoded in the registry of citizens.
都被編碼登錄在公民登記處
Your father stole the registry's Codex
你父親竊走了登記處的法典
and stored it in the capsule that brought you here.
將之藏匿在，載你飛往地球的太空船中
For what purpose?
那是為了什麼？
So that Krypton can live again
這樣克利普頓可以重生
on Earth.
就在地球上
Where is the Codex, Kal?
法典在哪裡，凱？
If Krypton lives again
若克利普頓重生
what happens to Earth?
那地球會怎麼樣？
The foundation has to be built on something.
我們必須把基礎建立在某處
Even your father recognized that.
就連你父親都懂這點
No, Zod.
不，薩德
I can't be a part of this.
我不能參與你的計劃
Then what can you be a part of?
那你要加入哪一邊？
No!
不
Zod!
薩德
No!
不
<font color="#D900D9">(SHACKLES CLANKING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Your father acquitted himself with honor, Kal.
凱，你父親光榮地死去
You killed him?
你殺了他？
I did.
沒錯
And not a day goes by where it doesn't haunt me.
這件事每天都困擾著我
But if I had to do it again, I would.
但若重新來過，我還是會這麼做
I have a duty to my people
我對我的人民有責任
and I will not allow anyone to prevent me from carrying it out.
我不會讓任何人 阻擋我履行我的職責
What's the sit-rep, major?
報告最新情況，少校
DSP pinged two bogeys launching from the alien ship.
偵測到外星飛船，發射兩艘飛行物體
- Put it up. - Yes, sir.
- 放到大螢幕 - 是的，長官
<font color="#808080">LARAMORE:</font> There it is.
在那裡
Re-task IKon-4
調整艾康四號
-  and get me a closer look. <font color="#808080">ANALYST:</font> - Yes, sir.
-  我要看清楚點  -  是的，長官
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> Command, the word of the day is trident.
這裡是指揮中心，安全密語是三叉戟
We have two alien craft on aggressive approach.
現在有兩架外星飛船逼進中
Ikon-4 coming online.
艾康四號已上線
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> Air speed?
飛行速度？
<font color="#808080">ANALYST:</font> 380 knots, entering Kansas Airspace.
以380節速度進入堪薩斯領空
Not responding to our hails.
他們對我們的溝通沒有回應
You're wasting your efforts.
你在浪費力氣
The strength you derived from the Earth's sun
你從太陽獲取來的力量
has been neutralized aboard our ship.
在我們船上被中和了
Here
在這裡
in this environment
在這樣的環境中
you are as weak as a human.
你跟人類一樣脆弱
<font color="#D900D9">(WHIRRING)</font>
Where did you come from?
你是從哪冒出來的？
The command key, Miss Lane.
中控鑰匙，蓮恩小姐
Thanks to you, I'm uploading to the ship's mainframe.
多虧妳，我被灌入太空船的主機裡了
Who are you?
你是誰？
I am Kai's father.
我是凱的父親
Can you help us?
你能幫助我們嗎？
I designed this ship.
這艘船是我設計的
I can modify its atmospheric composition
我可以改變大氣成份
to human compatibility.
以適應人類需求
We can stop them.
我們可以阻止他們
We can send them back to the Phantom Zone.
把他們送回幽靈黑洞區
How?
怎麼做？
I can teach you.
我可以教妳，請妳再轉教凱
And in turn, you can teach Kal.
Will you help me?
妳會幫助我嗎？
<font color="#D900D9">(ALARM WAILING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GASPS)</font>
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> The ship's crew are alerted.
船上組員已被告知
We need to move quickly.
我們要動作快
Retrieve the command key.
把中控鑰匙拿回來
<font color="#D900D9">(DOOR WHIRRING)</font>
- Did you do that? - Yes. Pick up her sidearm.
- 是你做的嗎？ - 對，把武器撿起來
<font color="#D900D9">(ALARM WAILING)</font>
What's happening?
發生什麼事了？
To your right.
朝右邊
Fire.
開火
Behind you.
在妳身後
Secure yourself inside the open pod.
進入分離艙，綁好安全帶
Safe travels, Miss Lane. It's unlikely
祝妳旅途平安，蓮恩小姐
we'll see each other again.
我們應該不會再相會
Remember, the phantom drives are essential in stopping them.
請記住，幽靈驅動系統 是阻止他們的關鍵
Move your head to the left.
把頭往左傾
<font color="#D900D9">(SCREAMING)</font>
Is it true what Zod said about the Codex?
關於法典的事，薩德說得是真的嗎？
Strike that panel.
敲碎那塊面板
We wanted you to learn
我們希望
what it meant to be human first
你先學會做人的道理
so that one day, when the time was right,
然後有一天，當時機來臨你能成為兩族人間的橋樑
you could be the bridgebetween two peoples.
你能成為兩族人間的橋樑
Look.
你看
Lois.
露意絲
You can save her, Kal.
凱，你可以救她
You can save all of them.
你可以救所有的人
<font color="#D900D9">(SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(BARKING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> You'll be safe here.
妳在這裡會很安全
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
妳沒事嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
I didn't wanna tell them anything, but they did something to me.
我不想告訴他們你的事 但他們對我動了手腳
- They looked inside my mind  - It's okay, Lois.
- 他們探索我的大腦  - 沒關係，露意絲
They did the same thing to me.
他們也這樣對我
Clark!
克拉克
<font color="#D900D9">(POLICE SIREN WAILING)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> The craft he arrived in
他當年乘坐的太空船
where is it?
在哪裡？
Go to hell.
去死吧
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
There.
在那裡
Unh!
<font color="#808080">FAORA:</font> The Codex is not here.
法典不在這裡
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Argh!
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> Ah!
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Where has he hidden it?
他藏哪去了？
I don't know.
我不知道
Where is the Codex?!
法典在哪裡？
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> Ahh!
You think you can threaten my mother?!
你敢威脅我媽？
<font color="#808080">ALL:</font> Ah!
<font color="#D900D9">(GROANS)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(CAR ALARM WAILING AND HORNS HONKING LOUDLY)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(CACOPHONY OF LOUD NOISES)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(BELL RINGING)</font>
What have you done to me?
你對我做了什麼？
My parents taught me to hone my senses, Zod.
我父母教導我，如何磨練我的感官
Focus
專注於
on just what I wanted to see.
我想看到的東西上
Without your helmet
少了頭盔
you're getting everything.
你能接收到所有一切
And it hurts
那很痛苦
doesn't it?
對不對？
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE CLAMORING AND SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Get away from the window.
離窗戶遠一點
Get inside. It's not safe.
進屋內，外面不安全
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(OVER RADIO)</font>  All players, this is Guardian. I am airborne mission commander.
所有人員，這是守護神，我是空中任務指揮官
I have previously encountered and observed
我之前曾近距離接觸並觀察過
the beings we're about to engage.
我們即將交火的生物
They are extremely dangerous and we have been authorized  to use deadly force.
他們極端危險，我們已被授權使用致命武力
<font color="#808080">PILOT 1:</font>  Roger, Guardian, we are inbound to target.
收到，守護神，我們朝目標飛去
<font color="#808080">PILOT 1:</font>  Cleared hot. Weapons free.
準備就緒，授權發射
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Copy, 11. Weapons free.
收到，11號，授權發射
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Thunder 11
tally three targets.
雷霆11號，總計三個目標
Thunder 11
雷霆11號
good hit. Request immediate re-attack.
直接命中，請立刻再度攻擊
<font color="#808080">PILOT 1:</font>  Roger, Guardian. We'll make a second gun run on a heading of 212 degrees.
收到，守護神，我們會再次朝212度掃射
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Thunder 11, eject!
雷霆11號，彈跳
Eject!
彈跳
Thunder 11, eject!
雷霆11號，彈跳
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  I have a bogey incoming!
有飛行物體逼近
Oh, shit.
死了
<font color="#D900D9">(WOMAN SCREAMS)</font>
You are weak. son of El.
你很脆弱，艾爾之子
Unsure of yourself.
自我懷疑
The fact that you possess a sense of morality
光是你具有道德觀這點
and we do not
而我們沒有
gives us an evolutionary advantage.
就讓我們擁有進化優勢
And if history has proven anything
如果歷史證實了任何事
it is that evolution always wins.
那就是進化永遠會勝出
<font color="#808080">PILOT:</font>  CCT, we're approaching
指揮控制塔
LZ Jayhawk. Get down in five.
我們接近降落點，五分鐘後抵達
<font color="#808080">RANGER 1:</font> Let's go. Go to the LZ.
快點，移至降落點
<font color="#808080">RANGER 2:</font> Roger, sarge. let's go!
收到，士兵，大步前進
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font>  All rangers, I need you
全體突擊隊員
to engage the targets.
請與所有目標交戰
<font color="#808080">RANGER 3:</font> Guardian, this is Badger 01.
守護神，這是B01分隊
What about the guy in blue?
那個穿藍衣的傢伙怎麼辦？
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font>  I said engage all targets.
我說過所有目標
<font color="#808080">PILOT 1:</font>  Contact. Contact.
有目標逼近
You okay?
你還好嗎？
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> We're auto-rotating, going in hard.
我們在自轉，即將墜機
Brace for impact.
做好撞擊準備
We're going in hard!
我們即將墜機
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Fallen angel. Fallen angel. Guardian is down.
直升機失事，守護神墜機了
I repeat, Guardian is down.
我重複，守護神墜機
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Guardian, do you read?
守護神，你收到了嗎？
Thunder 12, calling Guardian.
雷霆12號，呼叫守護神
- Do you read?  - Thunder 12  this is Guardian.
- 收到了嗎？ - 雷霆12號，這是守護神
Put down everything you've got north of my position.
集中火力在我以北的位置
- This will be danger-close.  - Copy, danger-close.
-  離我方非常接近  -了解 ，非常接近
Good luck, sir.
祝好運，長官
<font color="#D900D9">(GUN CLICKING)</font>
A good death is its own reward.
為理念奮戰而死是一種恩賜
<font color="#808080">FAORA:</font> You will not win.
你不會贏的
For every human you save
你每救活一個人類
we will kill a million more. Unh!
我們會多殺一百萬個
<font color="#808080">RANGER:</font>  Do we have an all clear? Do we have an all clear?
這地區淨空了嗎？ 這地區淨空了嗎？
Alpha team, sit-rep. Alpha team.
A小隊，請回報情況
Do you copy? Alpha team.
A小隊，收到了嗎？A小隊
This man is not our enemy.
這個人不是我們的敵人
Thank you, colonel.
謝謝你，上校
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> Mom?
媽？
I'm all right.
我沒事
<font color="#D900D9">(MARTHA CHUCKLES)</font>
Nice suit, son.
很帥的衣服，兒子
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> I'm so sorry.
我真抱歉
It's only stuff, Clark.
不過是些身外之物，克拉克
It can always be replaced.
永遠可以被替換
But you can't be.
但妳不能被取代
Mom, Zod said this Codex
媽，薩德說他在找的那個法典
he's looking for can bring my people back.
可以挽救我的族人
Isn't that a good thing?
那不是好事嗎？
<font color="#D900D9">(POLICE SIREN WAILING)</font>
I don't think they're interested in sharing this world.
我不覺得他們想要分享這世界
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Clark.
克拉克
Clark.
I know how to stop them.
我知道如何阻止他們
<font color="#808080">JAX-UR:</font> What happened down there?
下面發生什麼事了？
He exposed a temporary weakness.
他發現了我們短暫的弱點
It is of little consequence
那些小挫折不重要
because I have located the Codex.
因為我找到法典了
It was never in the capsule.
它從來都不在太空艙裡
Jor-el took the Codex
喬艾爾取走法典
the DNA of a billion people, then he bonded it
裡面存了十億人的DNA
within his son's individual cells.
他把它與自己兒子的細胞結合
All of Krypton's heirs
所有克利普頓的子嗣
living hidden in one refugee's body.
都存活在一個流亡者體內
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Does Kal-El need to be alive
那麼凱艾爾必須要活著
for us to extract the Codex from his cells?
才能從他細胞內取出法典嗎？
No.
不需要
Release the world engine.
釋出世界引擎
What just happened?
發生什麼事了？
The ship just split in two.
飛船剛才一分為二
Track one is heading east, track two to the southern hemisphere.
一艘往東飛，另一艘飛向南半球
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> How fast is that bogey moving? <font color="#808080">
飛行物體的速度有多快？
<font color="#808080">ANALYST 1:</font> Approaching Mach 24 and accelerating.
接近24馬赫並還在加速中
It's gonna impact somewhere in the Indian Ocean.
看來會撞擊南印度洋某處
The rest of the ship is descending.
剩餘的太空船正在降落
<font color="#808080">LARAMORE:</font> Put it on the board now.
放到大螢幕上
<font color="#808080">ANALYST 2:</font> Yes, sir.
是，長官
<font color="#D900D9">(BEEPING)</font>
<font color="#808080">LARAMORE:</font> Oh, my God.
我的老天
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL MURMURING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(HORNS HONKING)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Bring the phantom drive online.
連接幽靈驅動系統上線
We are now slave to the world engine.
我們現在由世界引擎操控
Initiate.
啟動
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> What have they hit us with?
他們用什麼打中我們？
Looks like some kind of gravity
看起來像某種重力武器
weapon. It's working in tandem with their ship.
和那太空船一起來回運作
Somehow they're increasing the Earth's mass
他們以某種方法增加地球質量
clouding the atmosphere with particulates.
用微粒狀物質遮蔽大氣層
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
They're terraforming.
他們在改造大地
What's that?
什麼意思？
Planetary engineering
用行星工程
modifying the Earth's atmosphere and topography.
改造地球的大氣和地形
Turning Earth into Krypton.
他們要把地球改造成氪利普頓星
- But what happens to us? - Based on these readings
- 那我們會怎麼樣？ - 根據這些讀數
-  there won't be an "us." <font color="#808080">ANALYST 1:</font> - General Swanwick, sir.
- 不會再有我們了   - 史旺威克將軍
I'm on with the control tower.
我跟控制塔連線了
Colonel Hardy's on his way and he's got Superman in tow.
哈帝上校正趕過來，他還帶著超人
Superman?
超人？
The alien, sir.
就是那個外星人，長官
That's what they're calling him. Superman.
他們是這樣叫他的，超人
We have a plan, general.
我們有個計劃，將軍
Is that what I think it is?
那是我想的東西嗎？
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> It's the ship he arrived in.
他是乘坐這艘太空船來的
This ship is powered by something called a phantom drive.
這艘船由幽靈驅動系統傳動
It bends space.
能夠彎曲時空
Zod's ship uses the same technology...
薩德的船也是使用相同科技
and if we can make the two drives collide
若能讓兩個超空間裝置撞擊
A singularity can be created.
就可能產生奇點
- Like a black hole. <font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> - Yes.
- 像是黑洞 - 對
So if we open up this doorway
如果打開這道門
they should be pulled back in.
理論上他們會被吸回黑洞
So you want us to bomb them with that?
你希望我們用那個轟炸他們？
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> General, that craft maxes out
將軍，這飛船頂多一萬七千磅
17,000 pounds, we can drop it from a C-17.
我們可以用C-17載運投擲
It's a viable plan.
這計劃可行
If I don't stop that machine over the Indian Ocean
如果我不阻止印度洋的飛船
the gravity field will continue to expand.
重力場會繼續擴張
If that thing is making Earth more like Krypton
如果那東西讓地球變成氪利普頓星
won't you be weaker around it?
那你接近它不是會變虛弱嗎？
Maybe.
或許會
I'm not about to let that stop me from trying.
我不會讓這點阻止我嘗試
You might want to step back a little bit.
妳或許該退後一點
Maybe a little bit more.
或許更多一點
Faora.
費歐拉
Take command.
由妳接管
<font color="#808080">FAORA:</font> - Yes, sir. - I need to secure the genesis chamber
- 是的，長官 - 我需要確保創始室的安全
and pay my respects to an old friend.
還要跟一位老朋友打招呼
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> Guardian en route to Metropolis
守護神現在前往大都會
package in tow.
運載著太空船
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> <font color="#D900D9">(OVER RADIO)</font>  Be advised, F-35s inbound to rendezvous point.
請注意 F-35出發前往集合點
You should have visual contact now.
現在應該已在目視範圍
<font color="#D900D9">(NOISE CACOPHONY)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTS)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(CACOPHONY STOPS)</font>
<font color="#808080">COMPUTER:</font>  Command key accepted. Genesis chamber coming online, sir.
創始室開始連線，接受中控鑰匙
<font color="#808080">JOR-EL:</font> Stop this, Zod
別這樣，薩德
while there's still time.
趁還來得及
Haven't given up lecturing me, have you, even in death?
你死後還是不放棄教訓我
I will not let you use the Codex like this.
我不會讓你這樣濫用法典
You don't have the power to stop me.
你沒有能力阻止我
The command key I have entered is revoking your authority.
我輸入的中控鑰匙，會駁回你的權限
This ship is now under my control.
這艘船現在歸我管
<font color="#D900D9">(COUGHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">PILOT 1:</font> Northcom, Lightning 1, request permission to unleash the hounds. <font color="#808080">
北方司令部閃電一號，請求許可投擲武器
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font>  - Lightning 1 you are clear to engage.
北方司令部閃電一號，授權進行攻擊
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> Send battle damage assessment when able. Out.
回報損傷評估，通話完畢
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font>  Avionics are going haywire.
航空電子設備都失靈了
The gravity field is pulling our missiles down. We gotta get closer.
重力場把我們的導彈往下拉，我們得更靠近
<font color="#808080">PERRY:</font> All right, everybody
好了各位
we're leaving. We're leaving the building now.
我們要離開了，現在撤出大樓
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#808080">PILOT 2:</font> I just lost my wingman.
我隊僚機剛遭擊落
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
求救！求救！求救！
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL CLAMORING)</font>
<font color="#808080">COP:</font> Everybody, this way! Come on!
大家往這裡逃，快點
Everybody, come on! Keep moving, keep moving.
大家快點，繼續跑
Jenny!
珍妮
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Perry!
派瑞
<font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> Go! There! Go!
快點，往那裡
Our people can co-exist.
我們的族人能共存
So we can suffer through years of pain trying to adapt like your son has?
你要我們像你兒子那樣，花費多年痛苦地去適應？
- You're talking about genocide. - Yes.
你在提倡種族滅絕
And I'm arguing its merits with a ghost.
對，而且我還在跟鬼魂辯論
We're both ghosts, Zod.
我倆都是鬼，薩德
Can't you see that? The Krypton you're clinging onto is gone.
你看不出來嗎？ 你所追求的克利普頓已經滅亡
Ship, have you managed to quarantine this invasive intelligence?
船艦，想辦法封鎖，這討人厭的影像訊息
- You'll fail. <font color="#808080">COMPUTER:</font>  - I have.
- 你會失敗 - 找到了
Then prepare to terminate it.
請準備終結它
I'm tired of this debate.
我厭倦了這場爭論
Silencing me  won't change anything.
就算逼我閉嘴也改變不了事實
My son
我的兒子
is twice the man you were.
比你強兩倍
And he will finish what we started.
他會完成我們的使命
I can promise you that.
我能向你保證
Tell me
告訴我
you have Jor-El's memories, his conscience.
你有喬艾爾的記憶和意識
Can you experience his pain?
但你能感受他的痛苦嗎？
I will harvest the Codex from your son's corpse
我會從你兒子屍體上，把法典拆解下來
and I will rebuild Krypton
然後我會把新的克利普頓
atop his bones.
建築在他的骨骸之上
<font color="#D900D9">(COUGHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">PERRY:</font> Jenny.
珍妮
- Jenny. Jenny, where are you? - I'm here!
- 珍妮，珍妮，妳在哪裡？ - 我在這裡
- I'm here. Here. <font color="#808080">PERRY:</font> - Jenny.
我在這裡，這裡
Hold on, hold on.
等等，等等
I'm stuck.
我被卡住了
- I can't get free. I'm stuck. - Okay.
我被卡住了，我出不來
We'll get you out of there, all right? Just sit tight.
我們會把妳救出來，等等
No, no, no!
不，不
Don't leave me.  We're not gonna leave you
別離開我，我們不會離開妳
Okay.  Lombard!
藍巴特
- Get your ass over here and help me. - Damn it.
- 快過來幫我  - 該死
<font color="#808080">PERRY:</font> We just gotta move this. <font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> Here.
- 我們只要把這個移開 - 這裡
Slide that in. You push, I'll pull, okay? Go.
把它插進去，你推我拉
<font color="#D900D9">(LOMBARD & PERRY GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> - Push! - Oh, my God.
- 用力 - 我的天啊
<font color="#D900D9">(LOMBARD & PERRY GRUNTING)</font>
越來越近了，快點推
<font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> It's getting closer! Come on, push!
Northcom, this is Guardian. Are we cleared?
北方司令部，這是守護神，我們可投擲了嗎？
Negative, Guardian.
還不行，守護神
<font color="#D900D9">(LOMBARD & PERRY GRUNTING)</font>
Come on! Push!
來啊，推
<font color="#D900D9">(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)</font>
He did it.
他做到了
Northcom, this is Guardian.
北方司令部，這是守護神
We're passing through phase line red. Good to go.
我們已經穿越警戒線，一切準備就緒
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> Godspeed, Guardian.
祝好運，守護神
Arm the package. You are cleared hot.
備好武器，授權投擲
We're lining up for the final run.
準備最後一次投擲
It's up to you and Hamilton now.
現在看妳和漢米頓的了
<font color="#D900D9">(GROANING)</font>
You gotta be kidding me.
別鬧了
<font color="#808080">HARDY:</font> Loadmaster, is the package ready to drop?
操作員，武器就緒可投擲了嗎？
Negative, Guardian.
還不行，守護神
There's something wrong. It's not supposed to do this.
不太對勁，不應該這樣
What's it supposed to do?
那該是哪樣？
- It's supposed to go in all the way. <font color="#808080">HAMILTON:</font> - Let me take a look.
- 應該要整個插入才對 - 讓我來看看
Co-pilot's aircraft.
副駕駛接手
<font color="#808080">CO-PILOT:</font> Co-pilot's aircraft.
We are lined up for the drop. What's the hold up?
我們到達投擲定點了，為何延誤？
We've had a setback.
我們遇到了點麻煩
Target that aircraft.
鎖定那架飛機
<font color="#D900D9">(COMPUTER BLEEPING)</font>
<font color="#808080">COMPUTER:</font> Target locked.
目標鎖定
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> Stop!
停
If you destroy this ship
如果你摧毀這艘太空船
you destroy Krypton!
就等於摧毀了克利普頓
Krypton had its chance.
克利普頓自己毀滅了自己
<font color="#D900D9">(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)</font>
<font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Miss Lane! It's not safe for you over there!
蓮恩小姐，站在那裡不安全
Miss Lane!
蓮恩小姐
<font color="#D900D9">(GUNFIRE)</font>
<font color="#808080">SOLDIER:</font> Move now! Go!
快點上，快
<font color="#D900D9">(NECK SNAPS)</font>
A good death is its own reward.
為理念奮戰而死是一種恩賜
<font color="#D900D9">(COMPUTER BEEPING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
Are they gone?
他們走了嗎？
I think so.
我想是的
He saved us.
他救了我們
You know, they say it's all downhill after the first kiss.
大家都說初吻之後就每況愈下
I'm pretty sure that only counts when you're kissing a human.
我很確信，那只在親吻人類時才算數
<font color="#D900D9">(THUMPING)</font>
Look at this.
你看這些
We could have built a new Krypton in this squalor.
我們本來能在這個豬窩，打造新克利普頓
But you chose the humans over us.
但你選擇人類，摒棄同胞
I exist
我存在
only to protect Krypton.
只為了保護克利普頓
That is the sole purpose for which I was born.
我出生只為了這目的
And every action I take
我的所作所為
no matter how violent
不管多麼暴力
or how cruel
多麼殘忍
is for the greater good
都是為了帶給我族人
of my people.
更高的利益
And now
而現在，我沒有族人了
I have no people.
My soul
我的靈魂
that is what you have taken
那就是你從我這裡
from me.
所奪走的
I'm going to make them suffer, Kal.
我要讓他們受苦，凱
These humans you've adopted, I will take them all from you one by one.
這些你所擁抱的人類，我要把他們一一奪走
You're a monster, Zod
你是個怪物，薩德
and I'm gonna stop you.
我會阻止你
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#808080">ZOD:</font> There's only one way this ends, Kal.
這場鬥爭只有一個結局，凱
Either you die
不是你死
or I do.
就是我亡
I was bred to be a warrior, Kal.
我生來就被培育為戰士
<font color="#D900D9">(GROANS)</font>
Trained my entire life  to master my senses.
一輩子受訓來強化我的感官
Where did you train? On a farm?
你是在哪受訓的，農場嗎？
<font color="#D900D9">(ZOD GROWLING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(GRUNTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(EXPLOSION)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(ZOD GRUNTING)</font>
If you love these people so much
如果你這麼愛這些人
you can mourn for them.
你可以替他們哀悼
<font color="#D900D9">(SCREAMING)</font>
Don't do this!
不要這樣
Stop!
停
<font color="#D900D9">(PEOPLE SCREAMING)</font>
Stop!
停
Never.
永不
<font color="#D900D9">(ALL SCREAMING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(SUPERMAN GRUNTS AND NECK SNAPS)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(PANTING)</font>
<font color="#D900D9">(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)</font>
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> Are you effing stupid?
你是白癡嗎？
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> It's one of your surveillance drones.
那是無人偵察機
<font color="#808080">SWANWICK:</font> That's a $12,000,000 piece of hardware.
那可值一千兩百萬美元
<font color="#808080">SUPERMAN:</font> It was.
現在不值錢了
I know you're trying to find out where I hang my cape.
我知道你們想查出我的藏身處
- You won't. - Then I'll ask
你們找不到的
the obvious question:
那我問個直接了當的問題
How do we know you won't one day act against America's interests?
我們怎麼知道 哪天你不會危害到美國安危？
I grew up in Kansas, general.
我在堪薩斯州長大，將軍
I'm about as American as it gets.
算是最道地的美國人
Look
聽著
I'm here to help
我是來幫忙的
but it has to be on my own terms.
但要照我的方式來
You have to convince Washington of that.
你得要說服華盛頓這點
Even if I were willing to try,
即便我想幫忙
what makes you think they'd listen?
你何以認為他們願意聽？
I don't know, general.
我不知道，將軍
Guess I'll just have to trust you.
我猜我只能相信你了
What are you smiling about?
妳在傻笑什麼，上尉？
Nothing, sir.
沒什麼，長官
I just think he's kind of hot.
我只是覺得他好帥
- Get in the car, captain. - Mm-hm. Yes, sir.
- 上車吧，上尉 - 是，長官
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font> He always believed you were meant for greater things.
他一直相信你註定會成就大事
And that when the day came
當那天到來時
your shoulders would be able to bear the weight.
你會有能力去承擔重責大任
Yeah, I just wish he could have been here to see it finally happen.
我只希望他能活著看到我成材
He saw it, Clark, believe me.
他看到了，克拉克，我相信
<font color="#808080">MARTHA:</font>  What are you going to do when you're not saving the world?
你不拯救世界時要做什麼？
- Have you given any thought to that? - I have, actually. Heh, heh.
- 你有想過嗎？ - 其實我有
I gotta find a job where I can keep my ear to the ground.
我得找個能讓我消息靈通的工作
<font color="#808080">CLARK:</font>  Where people won't look twice
而且要去危險地方時
when I want to go somewhere dangerous...
大家不會懷疑我的動機...
...and start asking questions.
也不會問我一堆問題
(星球日報)
<font color="#D900D9">(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)</font>
Come on, Lois. When are you gonna throw me a bone?
拜託，露意絲 妳何時才要給我機會？
Courtside seats to the game tonight.
今晚球賽場邊第一排座位
- What do you say? - I say
- 如何？ - 我認為
you should go back to trolling the intern pool.
你應該去騷擾那些新進實習小妹
You'll probably have more luck. Sorry.
成功率可能高些，抱歉
Courtside?
場邊第一排？
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Don't. Ha, ha, ha. - No.
- 不要 - 不
Lombard, Lane, I want you to meet our new stringer.
藍巴特、蓮恩，這是新特約記者
I want you to show him the ropes. This is Clark Kent.
帶他熟悉環境，這是克拉克肯特
Good luck, kid.
祝你好運，小子
<font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> Hey. Steve.
嗨，我是史提夫
- Nice to meet you. <font color="#808080">LOMBARD:</font> You too.
- 很高興認識你 - 我也是
<font color="#808080">LOIS:</font> Hi.
嗨
Lois Lane.
露意絲蓮恩
Welcome to the  Planet.
歡迎加入「星球」
Glad to be here, Lois.
很高興能加入，露意絲